njlottery.net 2006-09-02

# Privacy Policy

**NEW JERSEY STATE LOTTERY PRIVACY POLICY**

The following notice applies to the New Jersey State Lottery (NJ Lottery) Web site listed at www.state.nj.us/lottery/ Thank you for visiting the NJ Lottery Web site and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This statement addresses collection, use and security of and access to information that may be obtained through the use of the NJ Lottery Web site. This notice covers the following topics:

• | Information Collected and How it is Used  
---|---  
• | Personal Information and Choice  
• | Public Access to Information  
• | Cookies  
• | Security  
• | Disclaimer  
• | Contact Information  
  
Section A. Information Collected and How it is Used 

**Information Collected and Stored Automatically**  
If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the Web site, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit:

The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our Web site;   
The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;   
The date and time you access our site;   
The pages you visit; and   
If you linked to the NJ Lottery Web site from another Web site, the address of that Web site.   
We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors — learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits.

Likewise, your participation in the New Jersey Lottery VIP Club and any information provided to the New Jersey Lottery is strictly confidential and will not be sold or provided to anyone outside of the New Jersey Lottery or second-chance drawing partner(s) unless legally required.

**If You Send Us Personal Information**  
If you choose to provide us with personal information — as in an email, or filling out a form with your personal information and submitting it to us through our Web site — we use that information to respond to your message and to help us get you the information you have requested. We only share information you give us with another government agency if your inquiry relates to that agency, or as otherwise required by law. Moreover, we do not create individual profiles with the information you provide or to give it to any private organizations. NJ Lottery does not collect information for commercial marketing.

Section B. Personal Information Choice 

You may choose whether to provide personal information online.

"Personal information" is information about a natural person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes such things as individual's name, address and phone number. A domain name or Internet protocol address is not considered personal information.

We collect no personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us email, participating in a survey or completing an online form. You may choose not to contact us by email, participate in a survey or provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse the NJ Lottery Web site and read or download any information provided on the site.

**Privacy Warning**  
Email is not a secure medium. Personal information sent via the Internet can be intercepted. You may, therefore, wish to consider the advisability of sending messages that contain sensitive personal information to this Internet address.

NJ Lottery does not plan on divulging information collected or information disclosed voluntarily, but may be required to do so pursuant to a request under the Right to Know law, the common law Right to Know, other State or Federal law or pursuant to court order.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other that what it was intended when submitted, you may contact the Public Information Officer as shown in the Contact Information Section of this statement.

Section C. Public Access to Information

In the State of New Jersey, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government. At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals. Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws.

All the information collected at this site becomes public record that may be subject inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists.

Section D. Cookies 

NJ Lottery uses cookies to customize and enhance your browsing experience. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by Internet web sites to help identify users and enhance customer service. Cookies created by using the NJ Lottery Web site do not contain personally identifying information. The cookie feature is used only to store a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer and does not compromise your privacy or security.

Section E. Security 

NJ Lottery, as developer and manager of this Web site, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained. These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession.

Section F. Disclaimer

The NJ Lottery Web site and materials may contain hypertext or links to other Internet computer sites which are not owned, operated, controlled or reviewed by NJ Lottery. These links are provided solely as a courtesy and convenience to you, the visitor. When you link to one of these sites, you are no longer on the NJ Lottery Web site and this Privacy Notice will not apply. When you link to another Web site, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site. 

NJ Lottery, its officers or employees exercise no control over the organizations, views, accuracy, copyright or trademark compliance or the legality of the material contained on those servers and do not sponsor, endorse or approve the information, content, products, materials, opinions or services contained on such external sites. The visitor proceeds to these external sites at their own risk. NJ Lottery specifically disclaims any and all liability from damages which may result from accessing of a third party site which is linked to the NJ Lottery Web site or from reliance upon any such information.

Section G. Contact Information 

You may contact the NJ Lottery to review your personal information or request correction of your personal information by contacting:

> Public Information  
>  P.O. Box 041  
>  Trenton, NJ 08625-0041  
>  Fax: 609-599-5829  
>  Phone: 609-599-5875

Effective: November 9, 2001
